Mss.Rec.11 Mss.Rec.11
American Philosophical Society
Southern Tepehuan Materials
1948
Mss.Rec.11
American Philosophical Society
4.0 Reel(s)
Southern Tepehuan songs and stories originally recorded on wire by John Alden Mason in Xoconostle and Durango, Mexico in Februrary 1948, with consultants Gerónimo Aguilar and Pedro Aguilar. Music includes mitote songs and some traditional and popular songs. Stories include autobiographical stories and numerous unidentified texts. Mason's trip to the Tepehuan Indians in Mexico was sponsored in part by the American Philosophical Society and the University Museum of the University of Pennsylvania.
4 sound tape reels (1 hr., 10 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 7 in.
Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Recording contains some irregularity in speed.
Related Archival Materials
Collector documentation, transcriptions, translations, and other related materials are available in the John Alden Mason papers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift from John Alden Mason in 1952.
Indians of Mexico--Durango (State); Indians of Mexico--Languages; Sound recordings; Tepehuan Indians--Music; Tepehuan Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Tepehuan Indians--Social conditions; Tepehuan Indians--Social life and customs; Tepehuan language
- Audio recordings
  - Southern Tepehuan Text No. 1, 1948-02-01; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:49; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Wire recording) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Durango (Durango, Mexico); Indians of Mexico--Durango (State); Tepehuan Indians; Tepehuan language
  - Southern Tepehuan Text No. 2, 1948-02-01; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:08; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Southern Tepehuan Text No. 4, 1948-02-01; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:05; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
    Scope and Contents note
    Program runs slightly fast.
  - Southern Tepehuan Reel No. 2, Text No. 2, 1948-02-02; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:48; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - A Popular Song, 1948-02-02; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
    "Laya del oriente que me puso"
    Durango (Durango, Mexico); Indians of Mexico--Durango (State); Tepehuan Indians--Music
  - Mitote Music, 1948-02-02; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:22; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
    Durango (Durango, Mexico); Indians of Mexico--Durango (State); Tepehuan Indians; Tepehuan Indians--Music; Tepehuan Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Tepehuan language
  - Geronimo's trip to Durango, 1948-02-02; 01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:43; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
    Durango (Durango, Mexico); Indians of Mexico--Durango (State); Tepehuan Indians--Social conditions; Tepehuan Indians--Social life and customs; Tepehuan language
  - Text in Southern Tepehuan, 1948-02-03; 01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:41; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Text in Southern Tepehuan, 1948-02-03; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:07; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Story in Southern Tepehuan, 1948-02-03; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:36; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Traditional Tepehuan Song, 1948-02-03; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:36; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - An Account of the Life of the Southern Tepehuan, 1948-02-03; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:01; Aguilar, Gerónimo; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Southern Tepehuan Mitote Songs, 1948-02-10; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:09; Aguilar, Pedro; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
    Includes some commentary in English and Spanish.
    Indians of Mexico--Durango (State); Tepehuan Indians; Tepehuan Indians--Music; Tepehuan Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Tepehuan language; Xoconostle (Durango, Mexico)
  - Southern Tepehuan Mitote Song, 1948-02-10; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:53; Aguilar, Pedro; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Southern Tepehuan Mitote Song, 1948-02-10; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:25; Aguilar, Pedro; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Southern Tepehuan Mitote Song, 1948-02-10; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:30; Aguilar, Pedro; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Southern Tepehuan Mitote Song, 1948-02-10; 09-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:35; Aguilar, Pedro; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Southern Tepehuan Mitote Song, 1948-02-10; 09-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:38; Aguilar, Pedro; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Southern Tepehuan Mitote Song, 1948-02-10; 09-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:44; Aguilar, Pedro; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Southern Tepehuan Mitote Song, 1948-02-10; 09-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:09; Aguilar, Pedro; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  - Southern Tepehuan Mitote Songs, 1948-02-10; 09-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:39; Aguilar, Pedro; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967